♪The autumn wind slips in, never asking when I'll return♪
♪نسيم الخريف يتسلل، دون أن يسأل متى سأعود♪
♪Before the mirror, I comb my hair, lips parted just so♪
♪أمام المرآة، أمشط شعري، شفتاي مفتوحتان بهدوء♪
♪An old melody plays faintly, perhaps the answer to this life♪
♪لحن قديم يعزف بخفة، ربما هو جواب هذه الحياة♪
♪If fate leaves any trace at all♪
♪إذا كان القدر يترك أي أثر♪
♪Wild geese disappear in the woods, flowers wither at dusk♪
♪الإوز البري يختفي في الغابة، الزهور تذبل عند الغسق♪
♪How cruel the moonlight flooding the empty tower, wine growing cold♪
♪كم هو قاسٍ ضوء القمر الذي يغمر البرج الفارغ، والنبيذ يبرد♪
♪Long dreams and night rain tearing through the heart of Luoyang♪
♪أحلام طويلة ومطر الليل يمزق قلب لويانغ♪
♪Who still rides forth to keep a vow long left behind?♪
♪من لا يزال يركض ليفي بوعد طويل تم تركه؟♪
♪Paint the love and the hate♪
♪ارسم الحب والكراهية♪
♪With gentle strokes of ink, like a lone wild goose flying far away♪
♪بضربات حبر لطيفة، مثل إوزة برية وحيدة تطير بعيدًا♪
♪Frost and snow to sketch memories, drawn taut like a bow♪
♪الصقيع والثلج لرسم الذكريات، مشدودة مثل القوس♪
♪One arrow dyed in deepest red♪
♪سهم واحد ملون بأحمر عميق♪
♪The bitter chill within my heart♪
♪البرد المر في قلبي♪
♪The sorrow falling between your brows♪
♪الحزن الذي يسقط بين حاجبيك♪
♪Scalding memories lodged in my throat♪
♪ذكريات حارقة عالقة في حلقي♪
♪Burning away the warmth we once shared♪
♪تحرق الدفء الذي كنا نتشاركه♪
♪I would fade away with the candle's shadow♪
♪سأتلاشى مع ظل الشمعة♪
♪Sever the ties and stay behind alone♪
♪اقطع الروابط وابقَ وحيدًا♪
♪Let you go♪
♪دعك تذهب♪
♪Your sorrow lingers as you glance back♪
♪حزنك يبقى بينما تلقي نظرة للخلف♪
♪This longing has already worn me thin♪
♪هذا الشوق قد أضعفني بالفعل♪
♪We once vowed to grow old together♪
♪كنا قد تعهدنا بأن نشيخ معًا♪
♪But if fate bears no guilt, then why♪
♪ولكن إذا كان القدر لا يحمل ذنبًا، فلماذا♪
♪Does it play this song of tears for me alone?♪
♪يعزف هذه الأغنية من الدموع لي وحدي؟♪
=Destiny of Love= (Adapted from Lin Nan's novel, Destiny of Love.)
=قدر الحب= (مقتبس من رواية لين نان، قدر الحب.)
=Episode 4=
=الحلقة الرابعة=
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب القلب ولطيف)
That is how it all happened.
هكذا حدث كل شيء.
Who would've thought Prince Yunnuo would run right into me
من كان ليظن أن الأمير يونو سيصادفني
in the garden?
في الحديقة؟
You didn't blow your cover, did you?
لم تكشف عن هويتك، أليس كذلك؟
I don't think so.
لا أعتقد ذلك.
Prince Yunnuo seemed like an upright character.
بدا الأمير يونو شخصية مستقيمة.
I doubt he'd overthink it.
أشك في أنه سيفكر كثيرًا في الأمر.
Right.
صحيح.
Only you could come up with something
فقط أنت يمكنك أن تأتي بشيء
as shady as crawling through a dog hole.
مريب مثل الزحف من خلال حفرة كلب.
If we could just walk out the front gate,
إذا كان بإمكاننا فقط الخروج من البوابة الأمامية،
who would choose the dog hole?
من سيختار حفرة الكلب؟
Right.
صحيح.
Did you find that dog hole?
هل وجدت حفرة الكلب؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Where is it?
أين هي؟
Even if I told you, you wouldn't know.
حتى إذا أخبرتك، لن تعرف.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
It is well-hidden and completely safe.
إنها مخبأة جيدًا وآمنة تمامًا.
We will leave through it tomorrow.
سنغادر من خلالها غدًا.
Tomorrow?
غدًا؟
Don't waste time.
لا تضيع الوقت.
We're leaving now! Come on!
نحن نغادر الآن! هيا!
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Come in.
ادخل.
I'm taking you to meet an important guest.
سأخذك لمقابلة ضيف مهم.
I understand you're not fond of dressing up,
أتفهم أنك لا تحب التأنق،
but for the sake of our residence's reputation,
ولكن من أجل سمعة مقر إقامتنا،
I need you to make an effort.
أحتاج منك أن تبذل جهدًا.
I will personally do your makeup today.
سأقوم بتجميلك شخصيًا اليوم.
What?
ماذا؟
You are doing my makeup?
أنت ستقوم بتجميلي؟
You know how to do makeup?
هل تعرف كيف تقوم بالتجميل؟
What is so hard about it?
ما الصعب في ذلك؟
(Did he find out something about me?)
(هل اكتشف شيئًا عني؟)
Perfect.
ممتاز.
Dress her.
ألبسيها.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
Yunnuo, sorry to keep you waiting.
يونغ نو، آسف لإبقائك تنتظر.
Greetings, Brother.
تحياتي، أخي.
No need to be so formal.
لا داعي لأن تكون رسميًا.
To welcome you,
لأرحب بك،
I specifically asked your sister-in-law to get dressed up.
طلبت بشكل خاص من زوجة أخيك أن تتأنق.
You are too kind.
أنت لطيف جدًا.
Yunnuo, please have a seat.
يونغ نو، تفضل بالجلوس.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
Aliya, you sit too.
علياء، اجلسي أنت أيضًا.
Is that really all right?
هل هذا حقًا مناسب؟
We are all family here.
نحن جميعًا عائلة هنا.
No need to be so stiff.
لا داعي لأن تكون متصلبًا.
Please, sit.
تفضل، اجلس.
Aliya,
علياء،
he is my second brother.
هو أخي الثاني.
Fu Yunnuo, Second Prince of Luzhao Kingdom.
فو يونغ نو، الأمير الثاني لمملكة لوزهاو.
Say something.
قولي شيئًا.
Prince Yunnuo.
الأمير يونغ نو.
There is no need to be so reserved.
لا داعي لأن تكوني محتشمة.
Didn't we just see each other earlier?
ألم نرَ بعضنا للتو؟
It seems like we did.
يبدو أننا فعلنا.
Your makeup today is something else indeed.
مكياجك اليوم مختلف حقًا.
What a surprise.
يا لها من مفاجأة.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
All the better.
كلما كان ذلك أفضل.
Since you have already met,
بما أنكما قد التقيتما بالفعل،
let's get straight to the point.
لننتقل مباشرة إلى النقطة الرئيسية.
The most important thing
أهم شيء
for a family is to really
للأسرة هو أن تفهم
understand one another.
بعضها البعض حقًا.
So, let me properly
لذا، دعني أقدمكما
introduce you both.
بشكل صحيح.
Aliya, Princess of the Xilin Kingdom.
علياء، أميرة مملكة زيلين.
16 years old, and 1.6 cm.
عمرها 16 عامًا، وطولها 1.6 سم.
She weighs almost 50 kg.
وزنها حوالي 50 كجم.
50 kg?
50 كجم؟
You lying...
أنت تكذب...
Speak truthfully.
تكلم بصدق.
Did I underreport your weight?
هل قللت من وزنك؟
Yunnuo, Second Prince of the Luzhao Kingdom.
يونو، الأمير الثاني لمملكة لوزهاو.
Handsome and refined,
وسيم وراقي،
with a gentle personality
ذو شخصية لطيفة
and well-versed in literature and history.
وخبير في الأدب والتاريخ.
You flatter me.
أنت تمدحني.
I'm certainly not as learned as you.
أنا بالتأكيد لست بمستوى علمك.
Even Father has praised
حتى أبي قد أشاد
your poetry.
بشعرك.
I have looked into it.
لقد بحثت في الأمر.
The Grand Tutor at the Academy of Literary Studies
المعلم الكبير في أكاديمية الدراسات الأدبية
says your writing is exceptional.
يقول إن كتابتك استثنائية.
You even achieved a level of talent exceeding that of Zi Jian.
لقد وصلت حتى إلى مستوى موهبة يتجاوز زي جيان.
He is immensely talented.
إنه موهوب بشكل كبير.
(What is he up to?)
(ما الذي يخطط له؟)
(What does he mean by all this?)
(ما الذي يعنيه بكل هذا؟)
(Yunnuo must be her ideal husband.)
(يونو يجب أن يكون زوجها المثالي.)
(Don't be too grateful now.)
(لا تكن ممتنًا للغاية الآن.)
(These two are laying it on way too thick.)
(هذان الاثنان يبالغان كثيرًا.)
I do not know much about literature,
أنا لا أعرف الكثير عن الأدب،
so I will leave you two
لذا سأترككما
to your chat.
لحديثكما.
Please carry on.
من فضلكما تابعا.
I will take my leave.
سأغادر الآن.
Aliya!
علياء!
Yuetao, pack up! We're leaving!
يويتاو، جهز! نحن مغادرون!
He has an unusual sense of makeup.
لديه حس غير عادي في المكياج.
Yunnuo,
يونو،
I have something very important to entrust to you.
لدي شيء مهم جدًا لأعهده إليك.
What exactly is this important matter?
ما هو هذا الأمر المهم بالضبط؟
A lifelong matter.
مسألة تدوم مدى الحياة.
Brother, you mean a lifelong matter?
أخي، تقصد مسألة تدوم مدى الحياة؟
Yes.
نعم.
(Since you two did not see each other's strengths just now,)
(بما أنكما لم تريا نقاط قوة بعضكما البعض للتو،)
(I will give you another chance to connect.)
(سأمنحكما فرصة أخرى للتواصل.)
Much better.
أفضل بكثير.
Is everything packed?
هل تم تجهيز كل شيء؟
All done.
تم كل شيء.
Come on! Let's go!
هيا! لنذهب!
Your Highness, what now?
صاحب السمو، ماذا الآن؟
I am taking you to a gathering of royal heirs.
سأخذك إلى اجتماع لورثة العرش.
A gathering?
اجتماع؟
Isn't it just you and your younger brother?
أليس الأمر مجرد أنت وأخوك الأصغر؟
I am not good at socializing.
لست جيدًا في التواصل الاجتماعي.
I'd rather not embarrass you.
أفضل ألا أحرجك.
We are married.
نحن متزوجان.
Going together is not embarrassing. It is expected.
الذهاب معًا ليس محرجًا. إنه متوقع.
Besides, this gathering only happens
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، هذا الاجتماع يحدث فقط
once a month.
مرة واحدة في الشهر.
Aliya, let's get going.
علياء، لنذهب.
Brother.
أخي.
Princess Consort Jin.
الأميرة القرينة جين.
We've been waiting for you, Yunnuo.
كنا ننتظرك، يونو.
Our very first Luzhao royal heir gathering
اجتماعنا الأول لورثة لوزهاو الملكيين
shall begin now.
سيبدأ الآن.
The first?
الأول؟
Yes, it is the first,
نعم، إنه الأول،
but from now on,
ولكن من الآن فصاعدًا،
we will hold one
سنقيم واحدًا
every month
كل شهر
to strengthen our bonds.
لتعزيز روابطنا.
Yunnuo, what do you think?
يونو، ما رأيك؟
(Say no! Turn him down!)
(قل لا! ارفضه!)
If you think it is a good idea,
إذا كنت تعتقد أنها فكرة جيدة،
then I suppose I have no choice but to agree.
فأعتقد أنه ليس لدي خيار سوى الموافقة.
Good.
جيد.
I will host
سأستضيف
today's gathering.
اجتماع اليوم.
We are graced with excellent weather.
نحن محظوظون بوجود طقس ممتاز.
Let's fly kites.
لنطير الطائرات الورقية.
Fly kites?
نطير الطائرات الورقية؟
Your Highness, I do not know how.
سموك، أنا لا أعرف كيف.
I will head back. You all have fun.
سأعود. استمتعوا جميعًا.
Hold on.
انتظر.
Yunnuo knows how to fly them.
يونو يعرف كيف يطيرها.
Yunnuo, my legs are not in great shape.
يونو، ساقي ليست في حالة جيدة.
I will leave it to you to teach Princess Consort how to fly a kite.
سأترك لك مهمة تعليم الأميرة القرينة كيفية طيران الطائرة الورقية.
(He wants me to fly a kite with her?)
(يريدني أن أطير طائرة ورقية معها؟)
(What exactly is he trying to do?)
(ما الذي يحاول فعله بالضبط؟)
I feel chilly all of a sudden.
أشعر بالبرد فجأة.
Jiufeng,
جيوفينغ،
take me to the carriage so I can put on an extra layer.
خذني إلى العربة حتى أرتدي طبقة إضافية.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
(Flying a kite?)
(طيران طائرة ورقية؟)
(As if I am in the mood for that!)
(وكأنني في مزاج لذلك!)
(That guy gives me nothing but trouble!)
(ذلك الرجل لا يعطيني سوى المتاعب!)
Brother is usually swamped with state affairs.
أخي عادة ما يكون غارقًا في شؤون الدولة.
If he is taking the time to host a gathering today,
إذا كان يأخذ الوقت لاستضافة اجتماع اليوم،
it must be for your sake.
فلا بد أن يكون ذلك من أجلك.
Your bond with Brother seems strong.
يبدو أن رابطك بأخي قوي.
Well, we're married, so we just live life together.
حسنًا، نحن متزوجون، لذا نعيش الحياة معًا.
You are being modest.
أنت متواضع.
Father has high regards for Brother
الأب يكنّ تقديرًا كبيرًا لأخي
and he usually has a mountain of duties.
وعادة ما يكون لديه جبل من الواجبات.
It is rare for him to relax.
من النادر أن يسترخي.
I doubt he's that busy.
أشك في أنه مشغول إلى هذا الحد.
From what I see, he just eats, drinks,
من ما أراه، هو فقط يأكل ويشرب،
and sleeps around the residence.
وينام حول المكان.
Let's just get to kite-flying.
لنبدأ فقط في تحليق الطائرة الورقية.
All right.
حسنًا.
Here, you hold the kite.
هنا، أمسك بالطائرة الورقية.
I will get it up in the air in a moment.
سأجعلها تحلق في الهواء بعد قليل.
The kite's frame is broken.
إطار الطائرة الورقية مكسور.
Perfect.
ممتاز.
You spotted the problem instantly
لقد اكتشفت المشكلة على الفور
and fixed it so skillfully.
وأصلحتها بمهارة.
I imagine your medical skills must be just as precise.
أتخيل أن مهاراتك الطبية يجب أن تكون بنفس الدقة.
Surely Brother's chronic leg condition
بالتأكيد حالة أخي المزمنة في ساقه
would be easy for you to treat.
ستكون سهلة بالنسبة لك لعلاجها.
Well, we will see.
حسنًا، سنرى.
Depends on how serious it is.
يعتمد على مدى خطورتها.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
how did he get this injury?
كيف أصيب بهذه الإصابة؟
It's said Brother was caught in a fire when he was a child.
يُقال إن أخي وقع في حريق عندما كان طفلاً.
After that, he was unable to use his legs.
بعد ذلك، لم يتمكن من استخدام ساقيه.
Father searched the entire kingdom for the best physicians,
بحث الأب في جميع أنحاء المملكة عن أفضل الأطباء،
but none could cure it.
لكن لم يستطع أحد علاجها.
Hurry!
أسرع!
There's a fire!
هناك حريق!
Move!
تحرك!
Quickly!
بسرعة!
(No wonder...)
(لا عجب...)
All right. Let's fly the kite.
حسنًا. لنحلق الطائرة الورقية.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
(They make a fine pair.)
(إنهم يشكلون ثنائيًا رائعًا.)
(Once I leave the palace, I can rest assured.)
(بمجرد أن أغادر القصر، يمكنني أن أرتاح.)
You have to fly the kite against the wind for it
عليك أن تحلق الطائرة الورقية عكس الريح
to soar higher.
لتعلو أكثر.
Your Highness,
سموك،
Prince Yunnuo and Her Highness seem to be getting along well.
يبدو أن الأمير يونو وسموها يتوافقان بشكل جيد.
(If Yunnuo inherits the throne one day,)
(إذا ورث يونو العرش يومًا ما،)
(then Luzhao and Xilin can co-exist)
(فيمكن لـ Luzhao و Xilin التعايش)
(in peace and harmony for generations.)
(بسلام ووئال لأجيال.)
Want to give it a try?
هل تريدين تجربته؟
All right.
حسنًا.
When will you start treating Brother's condition?
متى ستبدأين بعلاج حالة أخي؟
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
Well...
حسنًا...
His Highness's injury has lasted so long.
إصابة سموه استمرت لفترة طويلة.
To treat it properly, I need to identify the root cause first.
لعلاجها بشكل صحيح، أحتاج إلى تحديد السبب الجذري أولاً.
(She is being tight-lipped about his treatment.)
(إنها تتحفظ بشأن علاجه.)
(She is guarding something from me.)
(إنها تخفي شيئًا عني.)
(This guy never stops talking.)
(هذا الرجل لا يتوقف عن الكلام.)
(If he keeps asking,)
(إذا استمر في السؤال،)
(I might not be able to deflect anymore.)
(قد لا أتمكن من التملص بعد الآن.)
Prince Yunnuo!
الأمير يونو!
Oh no, the kite string snapped!
أوه لا، انقطع خيط الطائرة الورقية!
Looks like we can't fly it anymore.
يبدو أننا لن نتمكن من تحليقها بعد الآن.
Prince Yunnuo, I'll take my leave then.
الأمير يونو، سأغادر إذن.
(What was Brother's real purpose)
(ما كان الغرض الحقيقي لأخي)
(for throwing this last-minute gathering?)
(لتنظيم هذا الاجتماع في اللحظة الأخيرة؟)
Aliya, why did you stop flying the kite?
علياء، لماذا توقفت عن تحليق الطائرة الورقية؟
The string broke.
انقطع الخيط.
There is nothing to fly anymore.
لم يعد هناك شيء لتحليقه.
Let's return.
لنعود.
No way.
مستحيل.
Our royal heirs' gathering includes
اجتماع ورثة العرش لدينا يشمل
more than just one activity.
أكثر من مجرد نشاط واحد.
You have to stay for the whole thing.
عليك البقاء للحدث بأكمله.
What else?
ماذا أيضًا؟
Archery.
الرماية.
Archery?
الرماية؟
Nice shot!
إصابة رائعة!
Yunnuo never misses.
يونو لا يخطئ أبدًا.
As expected of Luzhao's best archer.
كما هو متوقع من أفضل رامي في Luzhao.
Aliya, what do you think?
علياء، ما رأيك؟
Prince Yunnuo's accuracy is amazing.
دقة الأمير يونو مذهلة.
It is like watching Hou Yi himself.
كأنني أشاهد Hou Yi نفسه.
That's too high praise.
هذا مدح مبالغ فيه.
Not at all.
على الإطلاق.
Yunnuo is not only accurate,
يونو ليس دقيقًا فقط،
but he is also fast and powerful too.
بل إنه سريع وقوي أيضًا.
His arrows can pierce through the toughest targets.
يمكن لسهامه اختراق أصعب الأهداف.
Don't you want to see him do it?
ألا تريدين رؤيته يفعل ذلك؟
I really don't...
أنا حقًا لا...
Oh, don't be shy now.
أوه، لا تكوني خجولة الآن.
Yunnuo, show her a trick shot.
يونو، أرها طلقة خدعة.
(That cloud pattern...)
(ذلك النمط السحابي...)
Marvelous!
رائع!
Your Highness, are you okay?
سموك، هل أنت بخير؟
Are you hurt?
هل أصبت؟
I got such a huge tear! How can I be all right?
لدي تمزق كبير! كيف يمكنني أن أكون بخير؟
Why are you holding a gathering out here
لماذا تقيمون تجمعًا هنا
in the middle of nowhere?
في وسط اللا مكان؟
Even the jade pendant got ruined.
حتى تميمة اليشم قد تلفت.
What a shame.
يا للأسف.
(Could the cloud pattern be connected to Prince Yunnuo?)
(هل يمكن أن يكون نمط السحابة مرتبطًا بالأمير يونو؟)
(Prince Jin's Residence)
(مقر الأمير جين)
What? You are not running away anymore?
ماذا؟ أنت لم تعد تهرب بعد الآن؟
Not anymore.
ليس بعد الآن.
My mother left me an important Golden Box before she passed away,
تركت لي أمي صندوقًا ذهبيًا مهمًا قبل وفاتها،
and Prince Yunnuo's jade pendant
وتميمة اليشم للأمير يونو
has the exact same cloud design as it.
تحمل نفس تصميم السحابة تمامًا.
I finally found a clue.
لقد وجدت أخيرًا دليلًا.
I can't leave now.
لا يمكنني المغادرة الآن.
But...
لكن...
Your Highness.
سموك.
Come here.
تعال هنا.
You are hurt. Why have you not treated it yet?
أنت مصاب. لماذا لم تعالجه بعد؟
Sit.
اجلس.
Jiufeng.
جيوفينغ.
You got injured saving me.
لقد أصبت أثناء إنقاذي.
I will make sure to repay that debt.
سأحرص على سداد هذا الدين.
Your Highness,
سموك،
I married you.
لقد تزوجتك.
Of course, your safety is what I care about most.
بالطبع، سلامتك هي ما أهتم به أكثر.
Aliya...
علياء...
Your Highness, I'm fine.
سموك، أنا بخير.
But could you agree
لكن هل يمكنك الموافقة
to one small request?
على طلب صغير؟
Say it.
قلها.
Your Highness,
سموك،
would you allow me to come and go freely
هل تسمح لي بالدخول والخروج بحرية
from this residence from now on?
من هذا المقر من الآن فصاعدًا؟
Okay.
حسنًا.
(Finally!)
(أخيرًا!)
(I can return to Everything Guild again!)
(يمكنني العودة إلى نقابة كل شيء مرة أخرى!)
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة كل شيء)
Ji Mo!
جي مو!
Mr. Ji!
السيد جي!
Strange. Where's everyone?
غريب. أين الجميع؟
I've missed this place.
لقد افتقدت هذا المكان.
There's no place like home.
لا يوجد مكان مثل المنزل.
Even the air is nice and homey here.
حتى الهواء هنا لطيف ومريح.
With all this,
مع كل هذا،
Everything Guild could run three years without taking an order.
يمكن لنقابة كل شيء أن تعمل لثلاث سنوات دون تلقي طلب.
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
Mother,
أمي،
I finally found a lead on the Golden Box you left me.
لقد وجدت أخيرًا دليلًا عن الصندوق الذهبي الذي تركته لي.
I found the same cloud pattern
لقد وجدت نفس نمط السحب
that's on the box.
الموجود على الصندوق.
Rest assured.
اطمئني.
I will follow the clues,
سأتبع الأدلة،
open the box,
سأفتح الصندوق،
and find Father.
وأجد أبي.
It has been so long since I was last here.
لقد مر وقت طويل منذ آخر مرة كنت هنا.
Look at all this dust.
انظري إلى كل هذا الغبار.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
(Aliya?)
(علياء؟)
(I thought she had already escaped the capital!)
(ظننت أنها قد هربت بالفعل من العاصمة!)
Thief! How dare you sneak in here!
لص! كيف تجرؤ على التسلل إلى هنا!
No...
لا...
I'm not a thief!
أنا لست لصًا!
- Stop right there, you thief! - Don't you remember me?
- توقف هنا أيها اللص! - ألا تتذكرني؟
- I'm Ms. Qiao! Qiao Manman! - Stop!
- أنا الآنسة تشياو! تشياو مانمان! - توقف!
- Quit running! - Stop this!
- توقف عن الركض! - توقف عن هذا!
Why are you making such a racket
لماذا تصنع كل هذا الضجة
in the middle of the night, Fang?
في منتصف الليل، فانغ؟
There's a thief!
هناك لص!
Manman.
مانمان.
Mr. Ji.
السيد جي.
Where on earth have you been the past couple of days?
أين كنت في الأيام القليلة الماضية؟
You had me worried sick!
لقد جعلتني قلقة للغاية!
Manman...
مانمان...
Mr. Ji...
السيد جي...
Where have you been, Manman?
أين كنت، مانمان؟
Let me have a look at you.
دعني أنظر إليك.
Look at me.
انظري إلي.
You've lost weight.
لقد فقدت وزنك.
I've lost weight, Mr. Ji.
لقد فقدت وزني، سيد جي.
I've lost so much weight.
لقد فقدت الكثير من الوزن.
- Manman... - You have no idea how tired I've been.
- مانمان... - ليس لديك فكرة عن مدى إرهاقي.
I told Ji Mo to go find you,
أخبرت جي مو أن يذهب للبحث عنك،
but he just refused...
لكنه رفض ببساطة...
I didn't let his ears have a moment of peace.
لم أترك أذنيه تحظى بلحظة من الراحة.
Why shouldn't he go look for you, right?
لماذا لا يذهب للبحث عنك، أليس كذلك؟
You never came back,
لم تعد أبدًا،
so I kept worrying something bad had happened.
لذلك استمررت في القلق من حدوث شيء سيء.
Ji Mo found Aliya by the river.
وجد جي مو عليا بجانب النهر.
Looks like she hit her head
يبدو أنها أصابت رأسها
and lost her memory.
وفقدت ذاكرتها.
To avoid drawing attention,
لتجنب جذب الانتباه،
I kept her here.
أبقيتها هنا.
Manman!
مانمان!
It was the safest option.
كان هذا الخيار الأكثر أمانًا.
Where have you been all this time?
أين كنت طوال هذا الوقت؟
You had me worried sick!
لقد جعلتني قلقة للغاية!
Mo,
مو،
I've missed you so much...
لقد اشتقت إليك كثيرًا...
Keep your distance.
ابق على مسافة.
Stay there and explain yourself.
ابق هناك واشرح نفسك.
Fine. I'll tell you everything from the start.
حسنًا. سأخبرك بكل شيء من البداية.
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة كل شيء)
So you accidentally ended up marrying into Prince Jin's Residence?
إذن انتهى بك الأمر بالزواج في مقر الأمير جين بالصدفة؟
And you escaped this time?
وهربت هذه المرة؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Manman managed to get out
تمكنت مانمان من الخروج
and even brought back all that treasure.
وحتى جلبت كل ذلك الكنز.
Why don't we just run off
لماذا لا نهرب ببساطة
for good?
إلى الأبد؟
No, we can't.
لا، لا يمكننا ذلك.
Do you remember the Golden Box my mother left me?
هل تتذكر الصندوق الذهبي الذي تركته لي أمي؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
You could never figure out
لم تتمكن أبدًا من معرفة
how to open it, right?
كيف تفتحه، أليس كذلك؟
That was before.
كان ذلك من قبل.
I saw the exact same cloud pattern
رأيت نفس النمط السحابي بالضبط
on Prince Jin's younger brother's jade pendant.
على قلادة اليشم لأخ الأمير جين الأصغر.
It's a clue.
إنه دليل.
I think I'm close to opening the box
أعتقد أنني على وشك فتح الصندوق
and finding my father.
والعثور على والدي.
I know finding your father
أعلم أن العثور على والدك
has been your life's mission,
كان مهمة حياتك،
but your identity could be exposed at any moment.
لكن هويتك يمكن أن تنكشف في أي لحظة.
You could lose
يمكن أن تخسر
your life too.
حياتك أيضًا.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll take care of myself.
سأعتني بنفسي.
Manman,
مامان،
you've been through so much.
لقد مررتِ بالكثير.
Father,
أبي،
give her a pat for me too.
امنحها تربيتة من أجلي أيضًا.
Manman, you've been through a lot.
مامان، لقد مررتِ بالكثير.
Mo, you are being so dramatic.
مو، أنت تبالغ في الدراما.
What would you do
ماذا ستفعل
if a princess
إذا أصرت أميرة
insisted on sticking by your side, huh?
على البقاء بجانبك، هاه؟
Think about how you're going to get out of Prince Jin's Residence!
فكر في كيفية الخروج من مقر الأمير جين!
Why the sigh?
لماذا التنهد؟
Prince Jin has a leg condition that limits his mobility.
الأمير جين يعاني من حالة في ساقه تقيد حركته.
One of the purposes
أحد الأهداف
of this arranged marriage
من هذا الزواج المرتب
is to heal his leg.
هو علاج ساقه.
In that case, treat it.
في هذه الحالة، عالجها.
Oh, right. You don't know medicine.
أوه، صحيح. أنت لا تعرف الطب.
Just act like you know what you're doing.
فقط تصرف كما لو كنت تعرف ما تفعله.
Grab his leg,
أمسك ساقه،
pretend to massage it with a serious face,
وتظاهر بتدليكها بوجه جاد،
and then prescribe some tonics.
ثم وصف بعض المنشطات.
As long as you don't kill him, what is the harm?
طالما أنك لن تقتله، ما الضرر؟
Mr. Ji,
السيد جي،
when you put it like that,
عندما تضعها بهذه الطريقة،
it does make sense.
فإنها تبدو منطقية.
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب ورحيم)
Really? Princess Aliya is safe and sound?
حقًا؟ الأميرة علياء بخير وسلامة؟
She's at Everything Guild right now.
إنها في نقابة إيفريثينغ الآن.
The sooner we leave,
كلما غادرنا مبكرًا،
the sooner you can see your princess.
كلما أسرعت في رؤية أميرتك.
(I can't let Yuetao find out Aliya lost her memory.)
(لا يمكنني أن أدع يوتاو تكتشف أن علياء فقدت ذاكرتها.)
(She would lose it.)
(ستفقد صوابها.)
All right. As long as I get to see Her Highness soon,
حسنًا. طالما أنني سأرى سموها قريبًا،
I will do whatever you say.
سأفعل أي شيء تقوله.
Deal.
اتفاق.
Your Highness, someone is here to see you.
سمو الأمير، هناك شخص يريد مقابلتك.
I'm not seeing any guests.
لن أقابل أي ضيوف.
Understood. I will relay your message to Princess Consort Jin.
فهمت. سأنقل رسالتك إلى الأميرة القرينة جين.
Wait.
انتظر.
Did you just say Princess Consort Jin?
هل قلت للتو الأميرة القرينة جين؟
Yes, it's her.
نعم، إنها هي.
Let her in.
دعها تدخل.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سمو الأمير.
Is your wound serious?
هل جرحك خطير؟
It's just a scrape.
إنه مجرد خدش.
You are the cherished daughter of Xilin's Emperor.
أنت الابنة المدللة لإمبراطور زيلين.
A royal through and through, yet you are so unpretentious.
أنت ملكية بكل معنى الكلمة، ومع ذلك فأنت متواضعة جدًا.
You're quite different from the nobles here in the capital.
أنت مختلفة تمامًا عن النبلاء هنا في العاصمة.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
Prince Yunnuo, I want to ask you something.
الأمير يونو، أريد أن أسألك شيئًا.
Go ahead.
تفضل.
Last time during archery,
في المرة السابقة أثناء الرماية،
I noticed your jade pendant
لاحظت قلادتك من اليشم
had a unique pattern.
كان لها تصميم فريد.
I was wondering which painter designed it.
كنت أتساءل أي رسام صممها.
It was not designed by a painter.
لم يصممها رسام.
My mother created it.
والدتي هي التي صنعتها.
The Noble Consort?
الزوجة النبيلة؟
Correct.
صحيح.
Why are you interested in that pattern?
لماذا تهتمين بهذا التصميم؟
I just thought
أنا فقط ظننت
it looked special.
أنه يبدو مميزًا.
I was curious, that's all.
كنت فضولية، هذا كل شيء.
(Could the Golden Box my mother left me)
(هل يمكن أن تكون الصندوق الذهبي الذي تركته لي والدتي)
(be connected to Noble Consort?)
(مرتبطًا بالزوجة النبيلة؟)
(Hanyuan Hall)
(قاعة هانيوان)
Your Highness, Princess Consort Jin went to visit Prince Yunnuo.
صاحب السمو، الأميرة القرينة جين ذهبت لزيارة الأمير يون نوه.
Are you certain?
هل أنت متأكد؟
Absolutely.
بالتأكيد.
I see.
أفهم.
Continue to keep a close eye on her.
استمر في مراقبتها عن كثب.
You're dismissed.
يمكنك الانصراف.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، صاحب السمو.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
is something wrong?
هل هناك خطب ما؟
That Princess from Xilin,
تلك الأميرة من زي لين،
Prince Jin's new consort,
القرينة الجديدة للأمير جين،
turns out to be far more scheming than I expected.
تبين أنها أكثر مكرًا مما كنت أتوقع.
What do you mean, Your Highness?
ماذا تعني، صاحب السمو؟
I don't understand.
أنا لا أفهم.
She keeps getting close to Yunnuo.
إنها تستمر في التقرب من يون نوه.
She must be up to something.
لا بد أنها تخطط لشيء ما.
Your Highness, are you overthinking it?
صاحب السمو، هل تبالغ في التفكير؟
Why would a foreign princess want
لماذا ترغب أميرة أجنبية
to harm Prince Yunnuo?
في إيذاء الأمير يون نوه؟
Don't forget.
لا تنس.
She is not only a foreign princess,
إنها ليست مجرد أميرة أجنبية،
but she's also Prince Jin's new consort.
بل هي أيضًا القرينة الجديدة للأمير جين.
She is clearly spying on Yunnuo for Fu Chengjin.
من الواضح أنها تتجسس على يون نوه لصالح فو تشنغ جين.
I already have a plan to deal with her.
لدي بالفعل خطة للتعامل معها.
Go.
اذهب.
Bring Princess Consort Jin into the palace.
أحضر الأميرة القرينة جين إلى القصر.
I want to meet her myself.
أريد مقابلتها بنفسي.
What are you sighing for?
لماذا تتنهد؟
Do as I say!
افعل كما أقول!
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، صاحب السمو.
(Prince Jin's Residence)
(مقر الأمير جين)
Greetings, Prince Jin.
تحياتي، الأمير جين.
Princess Consort Jin.
الأميرة جين.
The Noble Consort has summoned Princess Consort Jin to the palace.
الزوجة النبيلة قد استدعت الأميرة جين إلى القصر.
The Noble Consort wants to see me?
الزوجة النبيلة تريد رؤيتي؟
Yes.
نعم.
Tell them I'll be right there
أخبرهم أنني سأكون هناك حالًا
after I freshen up!
بعد أن أستعد!
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
Perfect.
ممتاز.
(I was just looking for a chance to meet her.)
(كنت أبحث فقط عن فرصة لمقابلتها.)
I had better get ready quickly.
من الأفضل أن أستعد بسرعة.
Can't keep the Noble Consort waiting.
لا يمكنني تأخير الزوجة النبيلة.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Why would Noble Consort
لماذا قد تستدعي الزوجة النبيلة
suddenly summon Her Highness?
الأميرة فجأة؟
It's clearly not for something trivial.
من الواضح أن الأمر ليس تافهًا.
Something must be going on.
لا بد أن هناك شيء ما يحدث.
I should go see for myself.
يجب أن أذهب لأرى بنفسي.
Jiufeng.
جيوفينغ.
Why is she not here yet?
لماذا لم تأتِ بعد؟
Right...
حسنًا...
Princess Consort Jin has arrived.
الأميرة جين قد وصلت.
You're here, Princess Consort Jin.
أنتِ هنا، الأميرة جين.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي، سموك.
Your Highness,
سموك،
you truly are as stunning as they say.
أنتِ حقًا مبهرة كما يقولون.
Your beauty is enough to put flowers to shame.
جمالك يكفي لإحراج الزهور.
Not only do you have
ليس فقط لديكِ
a silver tongue,
لسانًا فصيحًا،
your sense of style is just as sharp.
بل أيضًا ذوقك في الأناقة حاد.
Your Highness,
سموك،
you are not just beautiful.
أنتِ لستِ جميلة فقط.
You also have exquisite taste.
لديكِ أيضًا ذوق رفيع.
I heard from Prince Yunnuo
سمعت من الأمير يوننو
that you created a unique cloud pattern yourself.
أنكِ صممتِ نمطًا سحابيًا فريدًا بنفسك.
You are truly amazing!
أنتِ حقًا مذهلة!
Might I be fortunate enough to learn from you someday?
هل يمكنني أن أكون محظوظًا بما يكفي لأتعلم منكِ يومًا ما؟
You are exaggerating. It is nothing special.
أنتِ تبالغين. الأمر ليس مميزًا.
Very well. As you wish.
حسنًا. كما تريدين.
Enough flattery.
كفى من الإطراء.
Lately, I have been suffering from terrible headaches.
في الآونة الأخيرة، كنت أعاني من صداع شديد.
I heard you're a divine physician from Xilin.
سمعت أنك طبيب إلهي من زي لين.
Maybe you could take a look at me?
ربما يمكنك أن تفحصني؟
(She's so unpredictable. What is she trying to do?)
(إنها غير متوقعة. ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟)
Are you unwilling?
هل أنت غير راغب؟
Yes.
نعم.
Not at all.
على الإطلاق.
Then, attend to my illness.
إذن، اعتن بمرضي.
Well...
حسنًا...
Your Highness,
سموك،
I came in such a rush today.
لقد أتيت على عجل اليوم.
I did not bring any of my tools.
لم أحضر أيًا من أدواتي.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
I have prepared everything for you.
لقد أعددت كل شيء لك.
Bring them in.
أحضروها.
Princess Consort Jin,
الأميرة القرينة جين،
will you start with acupuncture
هل ستبدأ بالإبر الصينية
or with the pulse?
أم بالنبض؟
Prince Jin has arrived.
الأمير جين قد وصل.
You never come here.
أنت لا تأتي هنا أبدًا.
This is a rare occasion.
هذه مناسبة نادرة.
Aliya just arrived in Luzhao.
عليا وصلت للتو إلى لوزهاو.
I was afraid she might not know our customs and unintentionally
كنت أخشى ألا تعرف تقاليدنا وقد تسيء
offend you, so I came along.
إليك دون قصد، لذا جئت معها.
If you and Aliya have no important matters to discuss,
إذا لم يكن لديك وعليا أمور مهمة لمناقشتها،
then allow us to take our leave
فاسمح لنا بالمغادرة
and return another day to pay proper respects.
والعودة في يوم آخر لتقديم الاحترام اللائق.
Oh, this headache of mine has returned again.
أوه، هذا الصداع قد عاد مرة أخرى.
A good physician has compassion.
الطبيب الجيد لديه شفقة.
But she seems heartless enough
لكنها تبدو بلا قلب بما يكفي
to let me suffer in pain.
لتتركني أعاني من الألم.
Your Highness, perhaps we should summon
سموك، ربما يجب أن نستدعي
the imperial physician to treat you.
الطبيب الإمبراطوري لعلاجك.
No physician can compare to her.
لا يمكن لأي طبيب أن يقارن بها.
I am in agony right now,
أنا في عذاب الآن،
and Prince Jin, you keep making excuses.
والأمير جين، أنت تستمر في تقديم الأعذار.
Are you perhaps holding a grudge against me?
هل تحمل ضغينة تجاهي؟
I only worry that Xilin's medical practices
أنا فقط أقلق أن ممارسات زي لين الطبية
may differ from ours,
قد تختلف عن ممارساتنا،
and your health could suffer.
وقد يتأثر صحتك.
It might be safer to leave it to our own physician.
قد يكون من الأكثر أمانًا ترك الأمر لطبيبنا الخاص.
The imperial physician has already tried.
الطبيب الإمبراطوري قد حاول بالفعل.
This headache is an old condition.
هذا الصداع حالة قديمة.
They said it cannot be cured.
قالوا إنه لا يمكن علاجه.
Right now, my only hope lies
في الوقت الحالي، أمل الوحيد يكمن
with Princess Consort Jin.
مع الأميرة الزوجة جين.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Even if I treat you, it would be my first time diagnosing the issue.
حتى إذا عالجتك، سيكون أول مرة أقوم فيها بتشخيص هذه المشكلة.
I know nothing of your medical history.
لا أعرف شيئًا عن تاريخك الطبي.
I worry that it might make things worse.
أخشى أن يجعل الأمور أسوأ.
You keep making excuses.
أنت تستمر في تقديم الأعذار.
Could it be that you do not actually
هل يمكن أنك في الواقع لا
know medicine at all?
تعرف الطب على الإطلاق؟
(Did she figure something out?)
(هل اكتشفت شيئًا؟)
(I have to fake my way through this.)
(عليّ أن أتظاهر خلال هذا.)
Your Highness,
سموك،
of course, I will treat you.
بالطبع، سأعالجك.
Allow me to take your pulse.
اسمح لي بفحص نبضك.
Much obliged.
أنا ممتن جدًا.
(She just wants to give you a hard time.)
(هي فقط تريد أن تجعل الأمور صعبة عليك.)
(You can't cure her)
(لا يمكنك علاجها)
(even if you're the best physician in the world.)
(حتى لو كنت أفضل طبيب في العالم.)
Your Highness's illness
مرض سموك
is neither serious nor trivial.
ليس خطيرًا ولا تافهًا.
What is your remedy, then?
إذن ما هو علاجك؟
As the saying goes,
كما يقول المثل،
when there is no flow, there is pain.
عندما لا يوجد تدفق، يوجد ألم.
Most headaches are caused by blocked meridians
معظم حالات الصداع تسببها قنوات الطاقة المسدودة
and stagnant qi and blood.
وركود الطاقة والدم.
Let me give you a massage to provide some relief.
دعني أقوم بتدليكك لتوفير بعض الراحة.
Proceed.
تابع.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Right now, I'm massaging
الآن، أقوم بتدليك
the Baihui Point for you.
نقطة Baihui لك.
If your headache flares up again,
إذا عاد صداعك مرة أخرى،
have the maid to massage it for you.
اجعل الخادمة تقوم بتدليكها لك.
(The Baihui Point?)
(نقطة Baihui؟)
Does it feel better?
هل تشعر بتحسن؟
Your technique is quite good.
تقنيتك جيدة جدًا.
Oh, but my head
أوه، لكن رأسي
still hurts very much.
ما زال يؤلمني كثيرًا.
Your Highness.
سموّك.
Today, we'll start with massage therapy.
اليوم، سنبدأ بجلسة العلاج بالتدليك.
When I return tonight,
عندما أعود الليلة،
I'll write a few prescriptions for you
سأكتب لك بعض الوصفات الطبية
to take morning and night.
لتتناولها صباحًا ومساءً.
You should recover in no time.
ستتعافى في وقت قصير.
Since you are taking charge yourself,
بما أنك تتولى الأمر بنفسك،
then I suppose it will be effective in three days.
فأعتقد أن العلاج سيكون فعالًا خلال ثلاثة أيام.
Otherwise,
وإلا،
I will charge you with contempt.
سأحاكمك بتهمة الازدراء.
♪The clouds stretch endlessly across the sky♪
♪تمتد السحب بلا نهاية عبر السماء♪
♪Looking down at eyes that gaze into the distance♪
♪أنظر إلى عيون تحدق في البعيد♪
♪Time keeps moving on♪
♪الزمن يستمر في التقدم♪
♪Whose footprints are left behind?♪
♪من ترك آثار أقدامه خلفه؟♪
♪It's more than just the courage to yearn♪
♪إنه أكثر من مجرد الشجاعة للشوق♪
♪It's destined that we cannot be close♪
♪مقدر لنا ألا نكون قريبين♪
♪Loving you is a secret♪
♪حبك سرٌّ♪
♪Afraid of disturbing you and then you'd distance yourself♪
♪أخشى أن أزعجك فتتباعد عني♪
♪Endlessly♪
♪بلا نهاية♪
♪How I wish I could dive into the sea♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أغوص في البحر♪
♪And gently rest♪
♪وأستريح برفق♪
♪It's to soothe the reason for your heart's pain♪
♪لتهدئة سبب ألم قلبك♪
♪If everything could overcome all barriers and fall in love♪
♪إذا كان كل شيء يمكنه تجاوز كل الحواجز والوقوع في الحب♪
♪Even the cloud and sea could be together♪
♪حتى السحابة والبحر يمكن أن يكونا معًا♪
♪Forget how far from shore and how dangerous it is♪
♪انسَ مدى البعد عن الشاطئ ومدى خطورته♪
♪We can't see♪
♪لا نستطيع الرؤية♪
♪If distance can't tear us apart and it's not hard to endure♪
♪إذا كانت المسافة لا يمكنها أن تفرقنا وليس من الصعب تحملها♪
♪Our tears will stay together♪
♪دموعنا ستبقى معًا♪
♪Don’t forget the love♪
♪لا تنسَ الحب♪
♪They could never have♪
♪الذي لم يستطيعوا الحصول عليه أبدًا♪